本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
欢迎关注微博 @懒死放映室
m -13 -10 l -13 -13 l 10 -13 l -6 3 l -8 1 l 3 -10 l -13 -10m -13 -14 l 13 -14 l 13 12 l -13 12 l -13 -14
m -13 -10 l -13 -13 l 10 -13 l -6 3 l -8 1 l 3 -10 l -13 -10
■
翻译  小蛮腰  屯栗子  回风舞雪兮
翻译  小肚腩  Reginamoon  艾瑞卡
校对  艾瑞卡   鸣谢  草草
斯塔克
Stark!
时间轴  吉吉  Ans  薛定谔的猫
他好像不太高兴
He doesn't seem happy.
你好  汉克
Hello, Hank.
后期 8T  总监  somehacker
你应该在莫斯科
You're supposed to be in Moscow.
我绕了个道
I took a detour...
去了你的防御实验室
through your defense lab.
告诉我这不是我想的那个东西
Tell me that isn't what I think it is.
那得看你是不是认为
That depends if you think
这是意图复制我实验成果的失败品
it's a poor attempt to replicate my work.
就算是你们三个  这也太胆大了
Even for this group, that takes nerve.
你受命前往俄罗斯
You were instructed to go to Russia.
我需要提醒你  皮姆博士  你是名军人
May I remind you, Dr. Pym, that you're a soldier...
我是个科学家
I'm a scientist.
那就有点科学家的样子
Then act like one.
皮姆粒子是从古至今
The Pym Particle is the
最具革命性的科学发明
most revolutionary science ever developed.
帮我们物尽其用
Help us put it to good use.
我让你们把我当仆人一样使唤
I let you turn me into your errand boy,
可你们现在居然试图盗取我的研究
and now you try to steal my research?
要是当时你也像现在这么猛地保护简妮特 皮姆博士
If only you'd protected Janet with such ferocity, Dr. Pym.
别冲动  汉克
Easy, Hank.
你再敢提我妻子试试
You mention my wife again
我就让你见识下什么叫猛
and I'll show you ferocity.
别看我  话是你说的
Don't look at me. You said it.
我正实提出辞职
I formally tender my resignation.
我们拒绝接受  正式的
We don't accept it. Formally.
汉克
Hank,
我们需要你
we need you.
皮姆粒子是个奇迹  拜托了
The Pym Particle is a miracle. Please.
别让你的过去决定未来
Don't let your past determine the future.
只要我还活着
As long as I am alive,
谁都休想得到那个公式
nobody will ever get that formula.
我们不该让他离开这栋楼
We shouldn't let him leave the building.
你已经骗了他了
You've already lied to him.
现在还想跟他开战吗
Now you want to go to war with him?
是的
Yes.
我们的科学家想复制他的成果还差得远呢
Our scientists haven't come close to replicating his work.
他刚才已经着实地教训了你一顿
He just kicked your ass, full-size.
你真想体验下
You really want to find out
在你看都看不到他在哪时  他有多厉害吗
what it's like when you can't see him coming?
我认识汉克·皮姆很久了
I've known Hank Pym for a long time.
他不是安全隐患
He's no security risk.
除非我们把他逼到那步
Unless we make him one.
现在
喜欢吗
You like that?
放马过来吧
Come get you some now.
你连动都没动一下
You didn't even move.
是啊
Nah.
我要是打你左边呢  就下面这里
What if I come in on the left side, right? Just down here.
你看到这里了吗
You see this right here?
我会想你的  斯科特
I'm gonna miss you, Scott.
我也会想你的  桃子
I'm gonna miss you, too, Peachy.
你们这帮人的道别仪式真怪
Man, you guys got the weirdest goodbye rituals.
好了  散了吧
All right, break it up.
散了吧  散了吧
Break it up! Break it up!
圣昆廷监狱
斯科蒂
Scotty!
你好呀  哥们
What's up, man!
真该死
Damn!
哥们
Ha-ha! Hey, man.
你的眼睛怎么了
Hey, what's up with your eye?
你觉得呢
Oh. Well, what do you think?
桃子打的  临别赠礼
Peachy. It's a going-away present.
对哦  我去年留的疤还在呢
Oh, yeah. I still got my scar from a year ago.
可你知道吗
You know what?
我仍然是唯一一个把他打趴下的人
I'm still the only one who knocked him out.
我可没做到
Well, I definitely didn't.
谢谢你来接我  哥们
Thanks for picking me up, brother.
哥们  我的狱友出狱我能不来吗
Bro, you think I'm gonna miss my celly getting out?
你女朋友如何  哥们
Hey, how's your girl, man?
她把我甩了
Oh, she left me.
我妈也死了
Yeah, my ma died, too.
我爸被驱逐出境了
And my dad got deported.
但这车归我了
But I got the van!
-不错  -是吧
- It's nice. - Yeah, right?
还要谢谢你让我借住  我需要地方住
Thanks for the hook-up, too. I needed a place to stay.
当你看到沙发再说吧
You wait till you see this couch.
你肯定会很高兴的
You're gonna be really happy.
你会很快站稳脚跟的  看着吧
You're gonna be on your feet in no time. Watch.
希望如此
I hope so.
我还要把你介绍给一些人
And I gotta introduce you to some people.
一些非常有才的人
Some really skilled people.
-没兴趣  -得了吧
- Not interested. - Yeah, right.
不  说真的  我不要再坐牢了
No, I'm serious, man. I'm not going back.
我还有个女儿要照顾
I got a daughter to take care of.
你知道有案底的人不好找工作吧
You know that jobs don't come easy for ex-cons, right?
哥们  我可是电气工程硕士好吧
Look, man, I got a master's in electrical engineering, all right?
肯定没问题
I'm gonna be fine.
欢迎光临芭斯罗缤
Welcome to Baskin-Robbins.
想试一下我们的芒果水果风暴吗
Would you like to try our Mango Fruit Blast?
不用  谢谢
Uh, no, thanks.
给我来个汉堡吧  谢谢
Um, I will have... I'll have a burger, please.
我们这不卖汉堡
Oh, we don't... we don't make that.
那就椒盐卷饼  热的  加黄芥末酱
Pretzel. Hot pretzel. Like, mustard...
你们有黄芥末沾酱吗
Do you have mustard dip?
我们是冰淇淋店  芭斯罗缤
It's ice cream. Baskin-Robbins.
那就给我随便来个热的刚出炉的吧
I'll just do, like, whatever's hot and fresh.
哥们
Dude.
能到后面来聊两句吗  快点
Can I see you in the back, chief? Pronto.
没问题  戴尔
Sure thing, Dale.
达比  这白痴交给你了  谢谢
Darby, could you just, uh, take care of this idiot? Thanks.
戴尔
Hey, Dale.
进来
Come on in.
拿把椅子坐下吧
Pull up some chair.
在圣昆廷监狱待了三年
Three years at San Quentin, huh?
你查出来了
You found out.
芭斯罗缤总会查出来的
Baskin-Robbins always finds out.
我很抱歉  但是我
Look, I'm sorry, all right? But I...
没人肯雇我
No one would hire me.
非法闯入  重大盗窃罪
Breaking and entering. Grand larceny.
我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我已经金盆洗手了  我只是
I don't do it anymore. I just...
向你致敬
Respect.
我简直开心得不能再开心了
I couldn't be happier about it.
真的吗
Really?
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你真的给那些该死的亿万富翁颜色看了
You really stuck it to those billionaire SOBs.
我对你做的那些事了解得越多
The more I read about what you did and stuff...
我越觉得"我居然认识这家伙
I'm like, "Wow, I know this guy?
他现在归我管"
I'm in charge of this guy?"
我这份工作做的很开心
Well, I'm very happy in this job,
我很感谢有机会可以
and I really just appreciate the opportunity to...
你当然是被炒了
Well, you're fired, of course.
我不能留着你
I can't really keep you on.
等一下  什么  炒了
Wait, what? Fired?
是的
Yeah.
戴尔  那不是暴力犯罪
Dale, look, it wasn't a violent crime.
我是个好员工
I mean, I'm a good worker.
不  的确不是暴力犯罪  是酷炫型的
No, it wasn't a violent crime. It was a cool crime.
但我告诉你
I'll tell you what, though.
当然是私下的  不对外啊
This will be totally off the books, off the records,
如果你走的时候想拿上一杯
but if you want to grab one of those Mango Fruit Blasts
芒果水果风暴的话
on your way out the door,
我会假装没看到
I'll just pretend I didn't see it.
斯科蒂  怎么了
Hey, Scotty. What's up?
我还以为你在上班呢
I thought you were supposed to be at work.
刚被炒了
I was. I got fired.
该死的  他们查出你是谁了
Damn. They find out who you are?
芭斯罗缤总能查出来  哥们
Baskin-Robbins always finds out, bro.
芭斯罗缤可不是玩的
Baskin-Robbins don't play.
要吃华夫饼吗
You want some waffles?
好  给我来一个
Yeah, I'll take a waffle.
那位是科特
Oh. That's Kurt.
他在福尔松蹲了五年  他是电脑天才
He was Folsom for five years. He's a wizard on that laptop.
很高兴认识你
Nice meet you.
我也很高兴认识你
Yeah. Nice to meet you, too.
你是谁
Who are you?
戴夫
Dave.
维斯塔那票干的不错
Nice work on the Vista job.
维斯塔那票  没错
Vista job, yes.
不  不  我听说过这个打劫
No, no. I have heard of this robbery.
严格来讲  我没有打劫他们  打劫包括恐吓
Well, technically, I didn't rob them. Robbery involves threat.
我讨厌暴力  我偷了他们  我是个飞贼
I hate violence. I burgled them. I'm a cat burglar.
你是说你是个怂货
You mean you're a pussy.
他们对顾客漫天要价
They were overcharging the customers, right?
总计得有上百万
And it added up to millions.
他揭发了这件事结果被炒了
He blows the whistle and he gets fired.
他接下来做了什么
And what does he do?
他黑进了安保系统
He hacks into the security system
把上百万美金
and transfers millions
转回给了那些被骗的人账上
back to the people that they stole it from.
还把所有的银行记录都放到了网上
Posts all the bank records online.
还把那家伙的宾利开进了他家泳池里
And he drove the dude's Bentley into his swimming pool.
你这是在干吗
What are you doing?
为什么把我的人生故事告诉这俩人
Why are you telling my life story to these guys?
你想干吗
What do you want?
好吧
Okay.
我表兄两周前跟一个人
My cousin talked to this guy two weeks ago
聊到一票超完美的活
about this little perfect job.
不干
No way.
别别别  等一下  这个人
No, no, no. Wait! This guy...
正好是你不喜欢的那种
This guy fits your M.O.
不要
No!
我金盆洗手了  我不要再进监狱了
I'm finished, man. I'm not going back to jail.
是个拿着丰厚养老金退休的百万富翁
It's some retired millionaire living off his golden parachute.
这简直就是斯科特·朗的完美目标
It's a perfect Scott Lang mark!
我不在乎  我不干
I don't care. I'm out.
皮姆博士
Dr. Pym?
是的  我还活着
Yes. I'm still alive.
身份证明
ID?
有那个就够了吧
Perhaps that will suffice.
很抱歉  先生  请进
Very sorry, sir. Please come in.
那是汉克·皮姆吗
Is that Hank Pym?
早上好  汉克
Good morning, Hank.
霍普
Hope.
叫我一声爸会死吗
Would it kill you to call me Dad?
你能抽空来见我们
Dr. Cross will be so pleased that
克洛斯博士会很开心的
you could find the time to join us today.
简直是激动万分
More like "thrilled".
收到你发的邀请函
I was surprised to receive
我还真是意外呀  达伦
any kind of invitation from you, Darren.
今天是什么大日子
What's the occasion?
你会知道的  对吧  霍普
Oh, you'll see. Won't he, Hope?
里面已经准备好了  就等你了
We're ready for you inside.
还是不理你呀
Ouch.
看来有些旧伤是无法痊愈的
I guess some old wounds never heal, huh?
别担心  我会照顾好她的
Don't worry, she's in good hands.
你这次是来看好戏的
You're in for a treat.
好久不见  皮姆博士  退休生活还好吗
Long time, no see, Dr. Pym. How's retirement?
你的脸还好吗
How's your face?
你先请
After you.
在我们开始前
Now, before we start,
我想先介绍一位非常特别的嘉宾
I'd like to introduce a very special guest.
这个公司的创始人以及我的导师
This company's founder and my mentor,
汉克·皮姆博士
Dr. Hank Pym.
当我从皮姆博士手中接管了这家公司时
When I took over this company for Dr. Pym,
我便立刻开始研究一个
I immediately started researching a particle
可以改变分子间距离
that could change the distance between atoms,
并增加密度和力量的粒子
while increasing density and strength.
如此一个革命性的想法为何会
Why this revolutionary idea remained buried
一直被埋在汉克的众多研究中
beneath the dust and cobwebs of
积累尘土和蜘蛛网  我不得而知
Hank's research, I couldn't tell you.
但请想像一下
But just imagine,
一个昆虫大小的士兵
a soldier the size of an insect.
终极秘密武器
The ultimate secret weapon.
蚁人
An Ant-Man.
他们当初就是这么称呼你的  对吧  汉克
That's what they called you. Right, Hank?
有点傻  我知道
Silly, I know.
这只是宣传手段
Propaganda.
用来唬人的故事
Tales to astonish!
捏造出来吓唬苏联的故事
Trumped-up BS to scare the USSR.
汉克  可以请你告诉来宾们
Hank, will you tell our guests what you told me
我每一次问你"蚁人真实存在吗"
every single time I asked you,
你是怎么回答我的
"Was the Ant-Man real?"
这只是个传说
Just a tall tale.
没错
Right.
因为如此不可思议的事
Because how could anything so miraculous
怎么可能是真的
possibly be real?
我受到蚁人传说的启发
Well, I was inspired by the legend of the Ant-Man.
有了我缩小无机物材料的突破性进展
And with my breakthrough shrinking inorganic material,
我就想  有没有可能把人也缩小呢
I thought, could it be possible to shrink a person?
这有可能做到吗
Could that be done?
这不再是个传说了
Well, it's not a legend anymore.
尊敬的来宾们
Distinguished guests,
我自豪地向你们展示现代战争的终结者
I am proud to present the end of warfare as we know it.
黄衫
The Yellowjacket!
不
Oh, no.
黄衫是全能的战争武器
The Yellowjacket is an all-purpose weapon of war
它可以改变穿着者的大小
capable of altering the size of the wearer
能够轻松打赢战争
for the ultimate combat advantage.
在我们现今生活的时代
We live in an era
我们用来保护自己的武器
in which the weapons we use to protect ourselves
受到持续监视的削弱
are undermined by constant surveillance.
来回到简单的时代
It's time to return to a simpler age.
让人们可以公开地
One where the powers of freedom
使用自由的权利
can once again operate openly
来保卫自己的利益
to protect their interests.
一个全能型维和的机甲
An all-purpose peace-keeping vessel,
黄衫可以悄无声息地
the Yellowjacket can manage any conflict
解决地缘政治中的
on the geopolitical landscape
任何冲突
completely unseen.
在预防手段和战术袭击中
Efficient in both preventative measures
均有奇效
and tactical assault.
实际应用包括监视
Practical applications include surveillance,
工业破坏
industrial sabotage,
和清除和平道路上的一切障碍
and the elimination of obstructions on the road to peace.
只需一件黄衫
A single Yellowjacket
使用者即可享有执行保护措施的
offers the user unlimited influence
无限能力
to carry out protective actions.
在不久后的一天  一支穿着黄衫的军队
And, one day soon, an army of Yellowjackets
将在全球范围创造一个
will create a sustainable environment
幸福的可持续发展的环境
of well-being around the world.
黄衫
The Yellowjacket.
所以这就是件衣服
So, it's a suit?
别说这么粗俗  弗兰克
Don't be crude, Frank.
这不是件衣服  而是个机甲
It's not a suit, it's a vessel.
怎么了  这项发明没有打动你吗
What's the matter? You're not impressed?
不  让人印象深刻  但我也有顾虑
No, I'm impressed. I'm also concerned.
想像一下我们的敌人能用这项技术做什么
Imagine what our enemies could do with this tech.
我们应该好好聊一下这个问题  弗兰克
We should have a longer conversation about that, Frank.
我很重视你的意见
I really value your opinion.
谢谢大家莅临  霍普
Thank you for coming. Hope?
非常感谢诸位  我现在将带大家离场
Thank you very much, everybody. I will escort you out now.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好像有点震惊
You seem a bit shocked.
达伦  我尘封那些秘密是有原因的
Darren, there's a reason that I buried these secrets.
你终于承认了
So you finally admit it!
我们本可携手完成  汉克
We could have done this together, Hank.
但你却把机会毁了
But you ruined that.
所以你只停留在过去  我才是未来
That's why you're the past and I'm the future.
别这么做
Don't do this.
克洛斯博士
Dr. Cross?
你先卖给我  我出比你要价高20%的价格
You sell to me first, 20% over your asking price,
两周后我就可以付你现金
I can have the cash here in two weeks.
成交
Deal.
我们该行动了  汉克
We have to make our move, Hank.
他进展得怎么样了
How close is he?
他还没法缩小生物
He still can't shrink a live subject.
你就把衣服给我
Just give me the suit
我来永除后患
and let me finish this once and for all.
不行
No.
克洛斯完全信任我
I have Cross' complete trust.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
也不尽然
Well, that's not entirely true.
我想我找到了合适的人选
I think I found a guy.
谁
Who?
爸爸
Daddy!
小花生
Peanut! Oh!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
非常抱歉  我迟到了
I'm so sorry I'm late.
我不知道聚会几点开始
I didn't know what time your party started.
邀请上写了时间的
It was on the invitation.
他都没收到邀请
He didn't get an invitation.
可他还是来了
But he came anyway!
我不会错过宝贝女儿的生日聚会
Well, I'm not gonna miss my little girl's birthday party.
我去告诉妈妈你来了
I'm gonna go tell Mommy you're here.
别
Oh, you don't...
你来这儿干什么  郎
What are you doing here, Lang?
你没给过孩子一分钱的抚养费
You haven't paid a dime of child support.
现在  只要我乐意  就可以逮捕你
You know, right now, if I wanted to, I could arrest you.
好像我很愿意见你似的  帕克斯顿
It's good to see you too, Paxton.
你能来妈妈可高兴了  她喝水都呛着了
Mommy's so happy you're here, she choked on her drink.
看我给你带了什么
Hey, look what I have for you.
我能现在就打开吗
Can I open it now?
当然能  宝贝儿  今天是你的生日啊
Of course, sweetheart. It's your birthday.
你是我最最最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend.
那是什么玩意儿
What is that thing?
他好丑啊
He's so ugly!
我爱死他了
I love him!
我能拿给我朋友们看吗
Can I go show my friends?
当然能  宝贝儿  去吧
Of course, sweetheart. Go ahead.
你是我最最最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend.
我会给孩子抚养费的
Look, the child support is coming, all right?
不过有了前科就很难找到工作
It's just hard finding a job when you have a record.
我相信你能想法解决
I'm sure you'll figure it out.
不过现在
But for now,
-我希望你离开我家  -不可能
- I want you out of my house. - No way!
这是我女儿的生日聚会
It's my daughter's birthday party.
-这是我家  -那又如何
- It's my house! - So what?
-她是我闺女  -斯科特
- It's my kid! - Scott!
你不能说来就来  你知道的  走吧
You can't just show up here. You know that. Come on.
这是生日聚会啊
It's a birthday party.
我知道  但你不能说来就来
Yeah, I know, but you can't just show up.
她是我闺女
She's my daughter.
你根本就不懂怎么做父亲
You don't know the first thing about being a father.
玛姬  看在你是我初恋
Maggie, I tell you this as a friend,
我们还是朋友的份上  我告诉你
and as the first love of my life.
你的未婚夫是个混袋
Your fiance is an asshat.
他不是混袋
He's not an asshat.
喂  嘴巴放干净点儿
Hey, watch your language. Okay?
哪里不干净了  我说的是袋
What language? I said "Hat."
别吵了
Stop it.
真的吗  玛姬  就他
Really, Maggie? That guy?
你可以嫁给任何你喜欢的人
Come on! You could marry anyone you want,
为什么偏要选个条子呢
and you have to get engaged to a cop?
至少他不是骗子
At least he's not a crook.
我在努力  我已经改过自新  洗手不干了
I'm trying, okay? I've changed. I'm straight.
我找了份工作
I had a job and...
我想付抚养费
I wanna provide.
我花了很多时间思考  现在我明白了
I had a lot of time to think about it and I love her.
我非常爱她
So much.
我错过了太多
I've missed so much time
我想成为她生活的一部分
and I wanna be a part of her life.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
租套公寓
Get an apartment,
找份工作  付抚养费
get a job, pay child support.
然后我们再讨论探视孩子的问题
And then we will talk about visitation, I promise.
你是她的英雄  斯科特
You're her hero, Scott.
成为她心目中的那个人吧
Just be the person that she already thinks you are.
弗兰克  很遗憾
I'm sorry you have such
你对黄衫深表担忧
deep concerns about the Yellowjacket, Frank.
是啊
Yeah. Well, uh...
很不幸  我们不能为所欲为
Unfortunately, we can't just do whatever we want.
那样就好了
It'd be nice though, right?
但是得遵守法则
But there are laws.
什么法则  人的吗
What laws? Of man?
自然法则高于人的法则
The laws of nature transcend the laws of man.
而我要高于自然法则
And I have transcended the laws of nature.
达伦  我觉得你不懂
Darren, I don't think you understand...
我们还没解决所有问题
We still haven't worked out all the bugs.
永别了  弗兰克
Goodbye, Frank.
谢谢
Thank you.
我最近一直在想感恩这事
You know, I've been thinking a lot about gratitude lately.
今天早上  我在冥想的时候
And today, during my morning meditation,
得出了一个有意思的结论
an interesting thought occurred to me,
我觉得也适用于你
and I think it might apply to you, too.
什么结论
How's that?
感恩可以是原谅
Gratitude can be forgiveness.
我有好几年都活在对汉克·皮姆的愤恨中
I've spent years carrying around my anger for Hank Pym.
我把我的才华都奉献给了他
I devoted my genius to him.
我本来可以去任何地方工作
I could have worked anywhere.
我没选好导师
I chose my mentor poorly.
而你甚至别无选择
You didn't even have a choice.
他根本就不相信你
He never believed in you.
之前赶你走真是不好
It's a shame what we had to do,
可这都是被他逼的  对不对
but he forced us to do it, didn't he?
但我们不该生气  我们应该感恩
But we shouldn't be angry, we should be grateful.
因为作为失败的导师
Because his failures as a mentor,
失败的父亲
as a father,
是他逼我们一展鸿图
forced us to spread our wings.
达伦  你成功了
You're a success, Darren.
你能获得的一切都当之无愧
You deserve everything coming your way.
再过377天才能见到凯西
别作弊了
Stop cheating.
回来啦  能人
Hey, what's up, hotshot?
他可能没听见你说话
Maybe he didn't hear you.
生日聚会怎么样
How was the party?
跟我说说那个活
Tell me about that tip.
什么
What?
我想知道你说的那个活
I wanna know about that tip.
宝贝儿  开工了  现在就行动
Oh, baby, it's on! It's so on, right now.
别激动  我就想知道消息的来源
Calm down, all right? I just need to know where it came from.
要绝对可靠才行
It's gotta be airtight.
好
Okay.
我和表兄欧内斯托一起参加一场品酒会
I was at a wine tasting with my cousin Ernesto.
当时大部分是红酒
Which was mainly reds,
你知道我不喜欢红酒
and you know I don't like reds, man.
但有种玫瑰葡萄酒扭转了局面
But there was a rose that saved the day.
那天我们很愉快
It was delightful.
他跟我聊起一个姑娘
And then he tells me about this girl,
艾米丽  她以前经常跟我们鬼混
Emily, that we used to kick it with.
其实那是我摸过的第一对奶
It was actually the first pair of boobs I ever touched.
你扯远了
It's the wrong details.
这跟你要讲的事毫无瓜葛
It has nothing to do with the story.
重讲
Go.
他告诉我她现在有份工作
So, uh, he tells me that she's
是帮别人打扫卫生
working as a housekeeper now, right?
她在跟一个叫卡洛斯的家伙约会
And she's dating this dude, Carlos,
他是海湾那头的一个大佬
who's a shot caller from across the bay.
她把她雇主的情况告诉了他
And she tells him about the dude that she's cleaning for.
他雇主是个很牛的执行总裁
Right? That he's like this big-shot CEO
已经金盆洗手  但是超级有钱
that is all retired now, but he's loaded.
卡洛斯和欧内斯托在同一个垒球队
And so, Carlos and Ernesto are on the same softball team,
他们有天开始聊天
and they get to talking, right?
好戏来了  卡洛斯说  "伙计
And here comes the good part. Carlos says, "Yo, man.
"有个人有个超大的保险柜
"This guy's got a big-ass safe just
"就放在地下室  就放在那"
"Sitting in the basement, just chilling."
欧内斯托当然就来找了我
Of course Ernesto comes to me because
因为他知道我盗窃技能了得
he knows I got mad thieving skills.
当然  我问了他
Of course, I ask him...
艾米丽告诉卡洛斯告诉你
"Did Emily tell Carlos to tell you
告诉我那是个什么样的保险柜了吗
"To get to me what kind of safe it was?"
他说  没有
And he says, "Nah, dawg.
她只说保险柜超赞
"All she said is that it's super-legit
装在里面的肯定是好东西
"And whatever's in it, it's gotta be good."
什么
What?
老头有个保险柜
Old man have safe.
而且他这一周不在家
And he's gone for a week.
好吧  有个老头  他有个保险柜
All right. There's an old man, he's got a safe,
而且有一周不在家
and he's gone for a week.
就按这个来计划
Let's just work with that.
我说什么来着
You know what I'm saying?
座机线剪了  手机信号阻断
Landline's cut, cell signal's jammed.
今晚没人会打求救电话
No one will be making for distress call tonight.
通信检查
Comm check.
-收到  -收到
- Check. - Check.
要是出了状况  还有我呢
Hey, if the job goes bad, you know I got your back, right?
别担心
Don't worry.
不会出状况的
It's not gonna happen.
我就喜欢他自负的样子
I love it when he gets cocky.
厉害
Damn!
警报解除了
Alarm is dead.
漂亮
Nice.
好了  我进到房子里了
All right, I'm moving through the house.
大力士设备
门上是个指纹锁
There's a fingerprint lock on the door.
什么  欧内斯托没告诉我这个啊
It's got what? Ernesto didn't tell me nothing about that.
我们是不是完蛋了
Aw, man, are we screwed?
并不会
Not necessarily.
我进去了
I'm in.
没有触发警报  身手不错啊
No alarms have been triggered. He's in like the Flynn.
天哪
Oh, man.
怎么了
What is it?
他们没开玩笑  这个保险柜相当保险
Well, they weren't kidding. This safe is serious.
有多保险  斯科蒂
How serious are we talking, Scotty?
保险柜品牌
是卡本代尔牌的
It's a Carbondale.
1910年造
It's from 1910.
用的跟泰坦尼克号一样的钢材
Made from the same steel as the Titanic.
你能打开吗
Can you crack it?
关键在于  这种钢不怎么耐寒
Well, here's the thing. It doesn't do so well in the cold.
还记得那座冰山吗
Remember what that iceberg did?
记得  坑死了小李子
Yeah, man. It killed DiCaprio.
一船人都死了
Killed everybody.
老太太没死
Did not kill the old lady.
她还把宝石扔进海里了
She still throw the jewel into the oceans.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我把水倒进锁眼里
I poured water in the
用氮把水冻上
locking mechanism and froze it with nitrogen.
冰会膨胀  而金属不会
Ice expands. Metal doesn't.
-你现在在干什么  -等待
- What are you doing now? - Waiting.
等待
Waiting.
漂亮
Nice.
里面是什么  现金吗  珠宝吗
What is it? Cash? Jewels?
-什么也没有  -你说什么
- There's nothing here. - What did you say?
-是套衣服  -什么
- It's a suit. - What?
一套旧机车皮衣
It's an old motorcycle suit.
没有现金  没有珠宝  什么也没有
There's no cash, no jewelry, nothing?
没有
No.
白忙活一场
It's a bust.
非常抱歉  斯科蒂
I'm really sorry, Scotty.
我知道你需要这票活
I know you needed to score.
我以为我们是用老鼠
I thought we were using mice.
有区别吗
What's the difference?
开始实验34-C  有机物原子缩小实验
Commence Experiment 34-C. Organic atomic reduction.
达伦  也许我们该考虑
Darren, maybe we should think...
缩小有机物组织是这项技术的核心
Shrinking organic tissue is the centerpiece of this technology.
我不能带着半成品去见买家
I can't go to the buyers with half a breakthrough.
实验34-C结果
Experiment 34-C results,
失败
negative.
消毒工作台  带实验对象35-C来
Sanitize the work station. Bring in subject 35-C.
为什么把这个锁起来
Why would you lock this up?
这太奇怪了
This is so weird.
斯科蒂  在吗
Scotty, what's up, man?
不知道这是什么呢
I wonder... What is this?
从这下面看上去
The world sure seems different
世界还真不一样  是不是  斯科特
from down here, doesn't it, Scott?
什么  谁在说话
What? Who said that?
路易斯  我在下面
Luis, down here!
这是火的试炼  斯科特
It's a trial by fire, Scott. Or, in this case,
或者现在是放水
water.
你比自己想象的要坚强
Guess you're tougher than you thought.
我不想看这个
Oh, I don't want to see this!
路易斯
Luis!
奶奶的...
Son of a...
积尘袋已满
什么情况
What the hell?
对试驾来说不错了
Not bad for a test drive.
留着衣服  我会联系你的
Keep the suit. I'll be in touch.
不  不  不  谢谢了
No! No! No, thank you!
趴在地上
Get down on the ground!
你被捕了
You are under arrest!
我没偷东西
No, I didn't steal anything!
我刚把偷的东西还回去了
I was returning something I stole.
别动
Don't move.
我们都快相信
You know, you almost had us convinced
你真的改过自新了
that you were gonna change your ways.
她们都很看好你
They were really rooting for you.
这会伤透她们的心
It's gonna break their hearts.
你有访客
You got a visitor.
谁
Who?
你的律师
Your lawyer.
我的律师
My lawyer?
我说过我会联系你的  斯科特
I told you I'd be in touch, Scott.
我开始觉得
I'm starting to think
你更愿意待在牢房里了
that you prefer the inside of a jail cell.
天哪
Oh, man.
坐下
Sit down.
先生  对不起  我偷了衣服
Sir, I'm sorry I stole the suit.
我根本不想知道你为什么有这个
I don't even wanna know why you have it.
玛姬没看错你
Maggie was right about you.
你怎么知道
How do you know about...
怪不得她不让你接近凯西
No wonder she's trying to keep you away from Cassie.
世事开始变艰难的时候
The moment things get hard,
你就会回去犯罪
you turn right back to crime.
在我看来  你有一个选择
The way I see it, you have a choice.
要么在监狱里度过余生
You can either spend the rest of your life in prison,
要么回到你的牢房
or go back to your cell
等待进一步的指示
and await further instructions.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我也不指望你能明白
No, I don't expect you to.
但你现在没什么选择的余地
But you don't have many options right now,
坦白讲  我也没有
and quite frankly, neither do I.
你觉得当初
Why do you think
我为什么要让你偷那套衣服呢
I let you steal that suit in the first place?
什么
What?
第二次机会可是很难得啊
Second chances don't come around all that much.
所以下次你要是觉得看到了机会
So, next time you think you might see one,
我建议你仔细看看
I suggest you take a real close look at it.
你是我最最最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend!
你真的不想要别的玩具吗
Are you sure you don't want a different toy?
不  我喜欢这个
No, I love this one.
好吧  睡觉吧  我爱你
Okay. Well, get some sleep. I love you.
妈妈
Mommy?
爸爸是坏人吗
Is Daddy a bad man?
我听有些大人说他是坏人
I heard some grownups say he's bad.
不是
No.
爸爸有时只是有些迷茫
Daddy just gets confused sometimes, you know?
明智之选  你总算听进去了一回
Smart choice. You actually listened, for once.
从门下走
Under the door.
好吧  现在去哪里
Okay, where to now?
-稳住 -天呐
- Hang tight. - Oh, God.
什么  什么
What, what?
他跑哪儿去了
Where the hell did he go?
我不知道  他就那么消失了
I have no idea. He just vanished.
封锁周边五个街区  马上
Set up a five-block perimeter. Now!
退后  退后  退后
Get back! Get back! Get back!
-斯科特  这些是我的同伴  -什么
- Scott, these are my associates.  - What?
那只蚂蚁身上是背了个相机吗
Is that a camera on an ant?
是啊  当然了  为什么不呢
Yeah, sure. Why not?
车在哪
Where's the car?
没有车  我们用飞的
No car. We've got wings.
到达
Incoming!
把脚放在中心节点上  然后扶住胸腔
Put your foot on the central node and mount the thorax.
你在逗我吗
Are you Kidding?
-这东西安不安...  -你他妈快上去  斯科特
- How safe is... - Just get on the damn ant, Scott!
我为什么在一辆警车上
Why am I on a police car?
我难道不是不应该在警车上吗
Shouldn't I not be on a police car?
这样你就可以搭个顺风车
So they can give you a lift
通过他们五个街区的封锁
past their five-block perimeter.
好吧  下一步怎么办
All right. Now, what's the next move?
抓紧了
Hang on tight.
这个容易  我找到窍门了
Oh, this is easy! I'm getting the hang of this.
往上拉就能向上飞  就像骑马一样
Yank up to go up. It's like a horse.
你要让247失去平衡了
You're throwing 247 off balance.
等等  他的名字叫247吗
Wait, his name is 247?
他没有名字  只有编号  斯科特
He doesn't have a name, he has a number, Scott.
你知道一共有多少只蚂蚁吗
Do you have any idea how many ants there are?
也许它是...也许它是248
Maybe it's... maybe it's 248.
不不不不  要晕了  要晕了
No, no, no, no! Vertigo, vertigo!
不  我觉得它是247
No, I think it's 247.
等等
Wait.
抓紧了
Hang on tight!
我觉得我逐渐掌握窍门了
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
是我在控制247  他并非听命于你
I am controlling 247. He is not listening to you.
什么
What?
-我能提个小小的要求吗  -不能
- Can I make one little request? - No.
停下来  247  打住  打住
Stop, 247! Time out, time out.
不玩了
Time out.
斯科维亚事件该怪谁
好了  等一下
All right, hold on.
等等
Just wait!
假如我吐在了头盔里会发生什么
What happens if I throw up in this helmet?
这是我的头盔  斯科特  别吐里面
It's my helmet, Scott. You do not throw up.
让她停下来吧  好不好
Let's set her down, all right?
我头有点晕了
I'm getting light-headed.
坚持住  斯科特
Hang on, Scott.
我有点...
I'm getting a little...
不能睡过头
I need a snooze button.
5分钟后叫醒我
Hit me in 5 minutes.
你好
Hello.
你是谁
Who are you?
你就一直在那站着
Have you been standing there,
看我睡觉吗
watching me sleep, this whole time?
没错
Yes.
为什么
Why?
因为你上次来时  是来偷东西的
Because the last time you were here, you stole something.
听着...
Hey, look...
拟猛蚁亚科子弹蚁
Paraponera clavata.
巨型热带子弹蚂蚁
Giant tropical bullet ants,
昆虫蛰伤痛度的排名
施密特疼痛指数排第一
ranked highest on the Schmidt pain index.
我不在时就由它们在这盯着你
They're here to keep an eye on you when I can't.
皮姆博士在楼下等着你呢
Dr. Pym's waiting for you downstairs.
谁
Who?
这是谁的睡衣
Whose pajamas are these?
这要怎么走过去啊
How am I supposed to do this?
好吧  一步一步来
All right, just one step at a time.
你们不咬我  我就不踩你们  成交吗
You don't bite me, I don't step on you. Deal?
我可以破坏掉服务器
I could take down the servers
克洛斯不会发现的
and Cross wouldn't even know it.
我们不需要这个人
We don't need this guy.
我猜你已经见过我女儿霍普了
I assume that you've already met my daughter, Hope.
见过了  她真好
I did. She's great.
她不认为我们需要你
She doesn't think that we need you.
我们是不需要  我们自己就能搞定
We don't. We can do this ourselves.
我费劲千方百计让你偷了我的装备
I go to all this effort to let you steal my suit,
然后霍普就害你被捕了
and then Hope has you arrested.
好吧  我们可以试试
Okay, we can try this
一旦他失败了  我就自己上
and when he fails, I'll do it myself.
她有点焦虑
She's a little bit anxious.
和这次的活儿有关
It has to do with this job,
鉴于你现在坐在我对面的这个事实
which, judging by the fact that you're sitting opposite me,
我姑且认为你是感兴趣的
I take it that you're interested in.
什么活
What job?
要喝茶吗
Would you like some tea?
好啊
Sure.
我很佩服
I was very impressed with
你通过我的安保系统的方式
how you managed to get past my security system.
冰冻金属那招尤其聪明
Freezing that metal was particularly clever.
你当时在看着我吗
Were you watching me?
斯科特  我看着你有一会儿了
Scott, I've been watching you for a while.
从你抢了维斯塔公司开始
Ever since you robbed Vista Corp.
维斯塔公司前任员
牵扯进手法精妙的盗窃案
抱歉
Excuse me.
"偷了"维斯塔公司
"Burgled" Vista Corp.
维斯塔的安保系统
Vista's security system was one of
是业内最先进的
the most advanced in the business.
它本应该是无法攻破的
It was supposed to be unbeatable.
但是你攻破了
But you beat it.
要加糖吗
Would you like some sugar?
要  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
你猜怎么着  还是不要了
You know what? I'm okay.
你是怎么让它们做到那个的
How do you make them do that?
蚂蚁能搬动自身重量50倍的物体
Ants can lift objects 50 times their weight.
它们建造  耕作  相互合作
They build, farm, they cooperate with each other.
好吧  但是你是怎么让它们做到那个的
Right. But how do you make them do that?
我用电磁波
I use electromagnetic waves
来刺激它们的嗅觉神经中枢
to stimulate their olfactory nerve center.
我对它们说话
I speak to them.
我想去哪里都可以  我可以听见一切
I can go anywhere, hear anything,
看见一切
and see everything.
但你依然一无所知
And still know absolutely nothing.
我和克洛斯的见面要迟到了
I'm late to meet Cross.
皮姆博士
Dr. Pym?
你没必要举手  斯科特
You don't need to raise your hand, Scott.
抱歉  我就一个问题
Sorry, I just have one question.
你是说  她是谁  这他妈发生什么事了
Who are you, who is she, what the hell's going on,
我现在能回监狱吗
and can I go back to jail now?
和我来
Come with me.
40年前  我创造了一个公式
40 years ago, I created a formula
能改变原子间的相对距离
that altered atomic relative distance.
什么
Huh?
我得知了如何改变原子间的距离
I learned how to change the distance between atoms.
那就是那件衣服的动力
That's what powers the suit.
它运作的原理
That's why it works.
但这是很危险的
But it was dangerous.
过于危险了
It was too dangerous.
所以我将它藏起来了
So I hid it from the world.
从那时我便另起炉灶  开了自己的公司
And that's when I switched gears and I started my own company.
皮姆科技
Pym Tech.
没错
Yes.
我收了个年轻的学徒  名叫达伦·克洛斯
I took on a young protege called Darren Cross.
达伦·克洛斯
Darren Cross.
他可是个大人物啊
He's a big deal.
但在他成为大人物之前  他是我的助手
But before he was a big deal, he was my assistant.
我觉得自己看中了他的某些特质
I thought I saw something in him.
甚至把他当自己儿子了吧
The son I never had, perhaps.
他很有才华  但当我们关系越来越近时
He was brilliant, but as we became close,
他开始怀疑我有事没告诉他
he began to suspect that I wasn't telling him everything.
他听到了关于皮姆微粒的传言
He heard rumors about what was called the Pym Particle,
从此开始着了魔般地想重现我的公式
and he became obsessed with recreating my formula.
但我不愿意帮他
But I wouldn't help him.
所以他背叛了我
So he conspired against me
投票把我赶出了我自己的公司
and he voted me out of my own company.
他是怎么做到的
How could he do that?
董事会的主席是我的女儿  霍普
The board's chairman is my daughter, Hope.
她投了决定性的一票
She was the deciding vote.
但当她看到克洛斯差不多就要
But she came back to me
重现我的公式时  她回到了我身边
when she saw how close Cross was to cracking my formula.
这整个过程非常的不稳定
The process is highly volatile.
假如没戴着特制的头盔
If one isn't protected by a specialized helmet,
有可能会影响到大脑的作用
it can affect the brain's chemistry.
我不认为达伦知道这一点
I don't think Darren realizes this,
再说了  他自己也没有多稳定
and, you know, he's not the most stable guy to begin with.
所以  你想要我做什么
So, what do you want from me?
斯科特  我相信人人都该有赎罪的机会
Scott, I believe that everyone deserves a shot at redemption.
你相信吗
Do you?
相信
I do.
假如你能帮我的话
If you can help me,
我保证能帮你重新回到你女儿身边
I promise I can help you be with your daughter again.
现在  你准备好自我救赎了吗
Now, are you ready to redeem yourself?
百分百好了
Absolutely.
我那些入室盗窃的日子一去不复返了
My days of breaking into places and stealing shit are done.
您要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
我要你入室并且盗窃
I want you to break into a place and steal some shit.
你今晚回家吃晚饭吗
Are you gonna be home for dinner tonight?
郎的"律师"
是汉克·皮姆博士
皮姆科技的
回的  我得去拿些东西  发短信给我
Uh, yeah. I'll pick something up. Text me.
好吧  是好消息吗
Okay. Good news?
我不知道  就是个消息
Uh... I don't know. It's news.
你是在试图找到我爸爸吗
Are you trying to find my daddy?
是的  甜心
Yeah, I am, sweetheart.
我只是想确保你爸爸的安全
I just want your daddy to be safe.
希望你抓不到他
Hope you don't catch him.
这不是第一次这些人
This isn't the first time these guys
试图染指能改变世界格局的武器了
have tried to get their hands on game-changing weaponry.
那是米切尔·卡森  神盾局前任防御部长
That's Mitchell Carson, Ex-Head of Defense at S.H.I.E.L.D.
如今正赶着颠覆政府的勾当
Presently in the business of toppling governments.
他一直想要我的技术
He always wanted my tech.
除非我们能闯进去偷了黄衫
And now, unless we break in and steal the Yellowjacket
并且毁掉所有数据
and destroy all the data,
否则达伦·克洛斯就要掀起世界动乱了
Darren Cross is gonna unleash chaos upon the world.
我觉得首先我们应该去向复仇者们求助
I think our first move should be calling the Avengers.
我花了大半辈子
I spent half my life
努力不让这项科技落入斯塔克手中
trying to keep this technology out of the hands of a Stark.
我现在也绝不会亲手把它交过去
I'm sure as hell not gonna hand-deliver it to one now.
这可不是钢铁侠战衣那种小儿科
This is not some cute technology like the Iron Man suit.
这个能改变现实的结构
This could change the texture of reality.
影射复联2剧情
再说了  他们八成正忙着把城市从天上往下扔呢
Besides, they're probably too busy dropping cities out of the sky.
好吧  那你为何不直接派蚂蚁去呢
Okay, then why don't you just send the ants?
斯科特  它们只是蚂蚁
Scott, they are ants.
蚂蚁  它们能做很多事
Ants, they can do a lot of things,
但它们依然需要个领头的
but they still need a leader.
需要某人能渗透进
Somebody that could infiltrate a place
某个被设计成无法渗透的地方
that's designed to prevent infiltration.
汉克  我是个贼  明白吗
Hank, I'm a thief, all right?
我是说  我是个很厉害的贼
I mean, i'm a good thief,
但这个也太疯狂了
but this is insane.
他说得对  汉克  你自己也清楚
He's right, Hank. And you know it.
你见过影像画面了
You've seen the footage,
你知道克洛斯能干出些什么来
you know what Cross is capable of.
我几个月前就反对用他
I was against using him when we had months,
而如今我们只有几天了
and now we have days.
我来穿那套衣服
I'm wearing the suit.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
我了解那栋建筑的里里外外
I know the facility inside and out.
我了解克洛斯的想法
I know how Cross thinks.
我比任何人都了解这项任务
I know this mission better than anybody here.
我们需要你待在克洛斯身边
We need you close to Cross.
不然的话  这项任务没办法成功的
Otherwise, this mission cannot work.
我们没时间胡闹了
We don't have time to screw around!
霍普  拜托听我说...
Hope, please listen to me...
他是个罪犯  我是你女儿
He is a criminal! I'm your daughter.
不行
No!
她说得对  汉克
She's right, Hank.
我不是你要找的人
I'm not your guy.
你为什么不自己穿呢
Why don't you wear the suit?
你以为我不想吗
You think I don't want to?
我是不能穿
I can't.
我穿过好几年
I spent years wearing it,
而这衣服对我产生了不良影响
and it took a toll on me.
你是唯一的人选
You're our only option.
在霍普失去她母亲前
Before Hope lost her mother,
她曾经视我为世界上最伟大的人
she used to look at me like I was the greatest man in the world.
而如今她看着我  眼中只剩下失望
And now she looks at me and there's just disappointment.
对我而言已经太迟了
It's too late for me,
但你不一样
but not for you.
这是你的机会
This is your chance.
重新赢得你女儿眼中的崇拜的机会
The chance to earn that look in your daughter's eyes.
不要辜负你在她心中的英雄形象
To become the hero that she already thinks you are.
这无关拯救我们的世界
It's not about saving our world.
而是事关拯救她们的
It's about saving theirs.
靠  这番话说得真好
Damn. That was a good speech.
斯科特
Scott,
我需要你成为蚁人
I need you to be the Ant-Man.
正确地使用它
In the right hands,
人和衣服之间就会是一种共生关系
the relationship between man and suit is symbiotic.
衣服有力量  人则是利用那种力量
The suit has power. The man harnesses that power.
你需要变得灵巧  敏捷  最重要的是
You need to be skillful, agile, and above all,
你得要快
you need to be fast.
你要能够在极短的时间内缩小
You should be able to shrink and grow
和变大
on a dime.
让你的体型总能配合你的行动
So your size always suits your needs.
现在  穿过那个钥匙孔  斯科特
Now dive through the keyhole, Scott.
你起跑时是大的
You charge big,
然后变小穿过
you dive small,
之后再变大
then you emerge big.
废物
Useless.
当你变小时  力量就被压缩了
When you're small, energy's compressed,
所以你180斤的男性的力量
so you have the force of a 200-pound man
放在了0.25毫米大的拳头后
behind a fist a 100th of an inch wide.
你就像是一颗子弹
You're like a bullet.
你出拳太重了  会把人杀死
You punch too hard, you kill someone.
太轻了  就会像是爱抚
Too soft, it's a love tap.
换句话说  你得懂得如何出拳
In other words, you have to know how to punch.
在我监狱里待了三年  我知道怎么出拳
I was in prison for three years. I know how to punch.
打给我看看
Show me.
真差劲
Terrible.
你想要给我演示一下如何出拳吗
You wanna show me how to punch?
打吧
Show me...
这样出拳才对
That's how you punch.
她一直等着这个呢
She's been looking forward to this.
真是呢
No kidding.
霍普在一段困难时期学会了武术
Hope trained in martial arts at a difficult time.
他说的"困难时期"是指我妈妈去世的时候
Oh, by "difficult time," he means when my mother died.
她死于一场坠机事故
We lost her in a plane crash.
你不愿告诉我她是怎么去世的就够糟了
It's bad enough you won't tell me how she died.
你能不能别再重复那个谎言了
Could you please stop telling me that lie?
我们在干正事呢
We're working, here.
好了  小公主  我们归回正题吧
All right, princess. Let's get back to work.
你刚是想打手吗
Were you going for the hand?
我觉得这个调节器碍着我了
You know, I think this regulator is holding me back.
别乱动那个调节器
Do not screw with the regulator.
假如那个调节器坏了
If that regulator is compromised,
你会变成亚原子级
you would go subatomic.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是你会进入一个量子界
It means that you would enter a quantum realm.
那又是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是你会进入一个现实
It means that you would enter a reality
在那里一切关于时间和空间的概念
where all concepts of time and space
都没有意义了
become irrelevant
因为你会不断缩小
as you shrink for all eternity.
你所知和所爱的一切
Everything that you know and love
都将一去不复返
gone forever.
棒  要是没坏的话
Cool. Yeah, if it ain't broke...
你对衣服已经有所了解
You've learned about the suit,
但你还没了解你最好的伙伴
but you've yet to learn about your greatest allies,
蚂蚁
the ants.
大黑蚁  子弹蚁  狂蚁  火蚁
忠诚  勇敢
Loyal, brave,
也是你这次任务中的帮手
and your partners on this job.
长角立毛蚁  俗称狂蚁
Paratrechina longicornis. Commonly known as crazy ants.
快如闪电  也能导电
They're lightning fast and can conduct electricity,
可以烧掉敌人的电子仪器
which makes them useful to fry out enemy electronics.
你也没那么狂嘛
You're not so crazy.
你好
Hey!
你真可爱
You're cute.
刚才好吓人的
That was a lot scarier a second ago.
未来实验室有独立的供电设备
It looks like the Futures Lab has its own isolated power supply.
全天都有保安看守
There's a security guard posted around the clock.
我们要你解决他
We'll need you to take him out
然后关掉安保系统
to deactivate the security systems.
接下来是谁
Okay, who's next?
拟猛蚁亚科子弹蚁
Paraponera clavata.
我知道  子弹蚁是吧
I know. Bullet ants, right?
施密特疼痛指数第一位
Number 1 on the Schmidt pain index?
伙计们  我们之前在卧室见过
Hey, guys. Remember me from the bedroom?
黄衫保护罩是完全密封的
The Yellowjacket pod is hermetically sealed,
唯一的入口是一个
and the only access point is a tube
直径约为5毫米的管道
we estimate to be about 5 millimeters in diameter.
为什么我有种不好预感
Why do I have a sick feeling in my stomach?
管道口有防护镭射网
The tube is protected by a laser grid,
我们最多只能关闭15秒
and we can only power that down for 15 seconds.
你得在备用电源启动前
You're gonna need to signal the crazy ants to blow the servers,
指示狂蚁们去烧掉服务器
retrieve the suit, and exit the vaults
拿到衣服  撤离保险库
before the backup power comes on.
弓背蚁属木蚁
Camponotus pennsylvanicus.
又名大黑蚁
Alternatively known as a carpenter ant.
适合陆空运输
Ideal for ground and air transport.
等等  我认识他
Wait a minute, I know this guy.
我要叫他安东蚁
I'm gonna call him "Ant-thony."
很好  非常好
That's good. That's very good.
因为这次  你得学会
Because this time, you're really gonna
如何控制他
have to learn how to control him.
叫他们把糖放进茶杯里
Tell them to put the sugar in the teacup.
你还好吧  我伤到你了吗
Aw! You okay? Did I hurt...
汉克想让你出去做目标训练
Hank wants you outside for target practice.
衣服没有武器  所以我做了这些飞盘
The suit has no weapons, so I made you these discs.
红盘缩小
Red shrinks.
蓝盘放大
Blue enlarges.
火蚁
Solenopsis mandibularis.
咬人是出了名的
Known for their bite,
但火蚁们也是出色的建筑师
the fire ants have evolved into remarkable architects.
他们能帮你自由进出险境
They are handy to get you in and out of difficult places.
你能做到的  斯科特  加油
You can do it, Scott. Come on.
他们不听我指挥
They're not listening to me.
你得认真  专心注意力集中
You have to commit. You have to mean it.
不要走捷径  不要撒谎
No shortcuts, no lies.
羞辱他只会乱上加乱
Throwing insults into the mix
对任何人都没有好处  霍普
will not do anyone any good, Hope.
我们没时间惯着他了
We don't have time for coddling.
我们重点是要帮助斯科特
Our focus should be on helping Scott!
是吗
Really?
我们的重点就是这个吗
Is that where our focus should be?
霍普
Hope!
我不知道为什么要来找你帮忙
I don't know why I came to you in the first place.
我们没她成不了
We can't do this without her.
老天
Oh, God.
你得关好车门
You gotta lock your doors.
说真的  这片有很多怪人
I mean, really, there's some weird folks in this neighborhood.
你觉得这都是玩笑吗
Do you think this is a joke?
你知道他让你冒了多大的风险
Do you have any idea what he's asking you to risk?
你有个女儿
You have a daughter.
我做这些也是为了她
I'm doing this for her.
我妈妈去世时  我两周没见到他人
You know, when my mother died, I didn't see him for two weeks.
他肯定很伤心
He was in grief.
我也是  我当时才七岁
Yeah, so was I, and I was seven.
然后他再也没回来  没有真正回来
And he never came back. Not in any way that counted.
他直接把我送到寄宿学校
He just sent me off to boarding school.
要知道  我以为
You know, I thought,
这次危机
with all that's at stake,
可能是我们重归于好的机会
just maybe we might have a chance of making peace.
可事到如今他还是对我拒之千里
But, even now, he still wants to shut me out.
他不是想拒绝你  他信任你
He doesn't wanna shut you out. He trusts you.
那要你来干什么
Then why are you here?
来证明他爱你
It proves that he loves you.
霍普  看着我
Hope. Look at me.
我是来当炮灰的
I'm expendable.
找我就是为了这个
That's why I'm here.
你现在应该也意识到了
You must have realized that by now.
这就是为什么是我穿那套衣服而不是你
I mean, it's why I'm in the suit and you're not.
他宁愿全盘皆输也不愿意失去你
He would rather lose this fight than lose you.
所以说
Anyway...
我打电话报警的时候
You know, I didn't know you had a daughter
不知道你有个女儿
when I called the cops on you.
她叫什么
What's her name?
凯西
Cassie.
很美的名字
It's a pretty name.
你得整理思绪  斯科特
You have to clear your mind, Scott.
想法一定要明确
You have to make your thoughts precise.
这就是其中原理
That's how it works.
想想凯西
Think about Cassie.
想想你有多想见她  靠这个集中精力
About how badly you want to see her. And use that to focus.
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes
想想你想要蚂蚁们怎么做
and just think about what you want the ants to do.
做得好
That's good!
你母亲说服我
Your mother convinced me
让她也加入我的任务
to let her join me on my missions.
他们叫她黄蜂女
They called her the Wasp.
她手到擒来
She was born to it.
之后没有哪一天
And there's not a day that goes by
我不在后悔当初答应了她
that I don't regret having said yes.
那是1987年
It was 1987.
分裂派在苏联库斯科劫持了一个导弹发射井
Separatists had hijacked a Soviet missile silo in Kursk
并向美国发射了一枚洲际导弹
and launched an ICBM at the United States.
进入导弹内部的唯一方式
The only way to the internal mechanics
就是穿过固态钛
was through solid titanium.
我知道我得缩小到
I knew I had to shrink
比分子还小  才能解除导弹
between the molecules to disarm the missile.
但我的调节器受损太重
But my regulator had sustained too much damage.
你母亲
Your mother,
没有丝毫犹豫
she didn't hesitate.
简妮特  不要
Janet! No!
她关掉了她的调节器
She turned off her regulator
缩小到亚原子级
and went subatomic
解除了炸弹
to deactivate the bomb.
她牺牲了
And she was gone.
你妈妈是个英雄
Your mom died a hero.
接下来的十年时间
And I spent the next 10 years
我试图了解量子领域的一切
trying to learn all I could about the quantum realm.
你想把她找回来
You were trying to bring her back.
但我只了解到我们有多无知
But all I learned was we know nothing.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
是她自己的选择
She made her choice.
但你为什么不早点告诉我
But why didn't you tell me that sooner?
我是想保护你
I was trying to protect you.
我已经失去了你母亲
I lost your mother.
我不想也失去你
I didn't mean to lose you, too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好棒
This is awesome.
真的好棒
It's awesome, you know?
你俩终于解除隔阂  重归于好
You guys are breaking down walls, you're healing.
这很重要
It's important.
我把气氛毁了  是不是
I ruined the moment, didn't I?
没错  的确
Yes, you did. Yes.
我去泡点茶
I'm going to make some tea.
搞定
Nailed it!
好样的  安东蚁
That's a good boy, Ant-thony.
你训练的最后阶段是潜入
The final phase of your training will be a stealth incursion.
好冷
It's freezing!
你不能在衣服里加层绒吗
You couldn't make a suit with a flannel lining?
你得拿到这个信号诱饵的原型机
You must retrieve this prototype of a signal decoy.
我当年还在神盾局的时候研发的
It's a device that I invented during my S.H.I.E.L.D. days.
我们要用它来干扰
We need it to counteract the transmission blockers
克洛斯在未来保险库装的通讯拦截器
that Cross installed in the Futures vault.
现在正在霍华德·斯塔克的
It's currently collecting dust in one of Howard Stark's
纽约州北边的一个仓库积灰呢
old storage facilities in upstate New York.
应该是小菜一碟
Should be a piece of cake.
你在目标区域上空了
You're over the target area.
现在出发  斯科特
Disengage now, Scott!
A中队  走
Squadron A, go!
B队  走
B, go!
C队  走
C, go!
好了  安东蚁  这次别再把我甩下去了
All right, Ant-thony, please don't drop me this time.
从搬糖块到干这个差距也太大了
Oh, it feels like a big leap from sugar cubes to this!
保持冷静
Stay calm.
伙计们  我们可能有麻烦了
Guys? We might have a problem.
汉克  你不是说是个旧库房吗
Hank, didn't you say this was some old warehouse?
它不是
It's not!
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
-斯科特  快回来  -任务中止
- Scott, get out of there. - Abort!
立刻中止
Abort now!
没事  看着不像有人在
No, it's okay. It doesn't look like anyone's home.
安东蚁  飞到屋顶去
Ant-thony, get me to the roof!
他要把衣服搞丢了
He's gonna lose the suit.
他命都要丢了
He's gonna lose his life.
好了  我到目标建筑的屋顶了
All right, I'm on the roof of the target building.
有人在  斯科特
Somebody's home, Scott.
山姆  下面出什么事了
What's going on down there, Sam?
是猎鹰
It's the Falcon!
感应器说这里有东西  但我什么都没看到
I had a sensor trip but I'm not seeing anything.
等等
Wait a second.
任务中止  斯科特  立刻中止
Abort, Scott! Abort now!
没事的  他看不到我
It's okay. He can't see me.
我看得到你
I can see you.
他看得到我
He can see me.
你好  我是斯科特
Hi. I'm Scott.
他刚直接自报家门了吗
Did he just say, "Hi, I'm Scott"?
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
首先  我是你的粉丝
First off, I'm a big fan.
谢谢  你谁啊
Appreciate it. So, who the hell are you?
我是蚁人
I'm Ant-Man.
"蚁人"吗
"Ant-Man"?
怎么  没听过我大名吗
What? You haven't heard of me?
不  你是该没听过我
No, you wouldn't have heard of me.
你要说明你是来干什么的吗
You wanna tell me what you want?
我想过来拿个仪器
I was hoping I could grab a piece of technology.
借用几天  用完就还
Just for a few days. I'm gonna return it.
我得拿去拯救世界  你懂的
I need it to save the world. You know how that is.
我确实懂
I know exactly how that is.
锁定入侵者
Located the breach.
-马上逮捕他  -对不住了
- Bringing him in. - Sorry about this!
你他妈在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
入侵者为成年男性
Breach is an adult male,
好像有某种缩小装置
who has some sort of shrinking tech.
抱歉
Sorry!
听着  我真的很抱歉  对不起
Look, I'm sorry about this. Sorry.
够了
That's enough!
安东蚁  帮下忙
Ant-thony! A little help!
我看不见你了
I've lost visual.
他在我的翅膀里
He's inside my pack!
抱歉
Sorry!
你看起来人很好
You seem like a really great guy.
这事绝对不能被队长知道
It's really important to me that Cap never finds out about this.
你刚那也太不负责而且很危险
That was completely irresponsible and dangerous!
你威胁到了全盘计划
You jeopardized everything!
你拿到了
You got it.
干得好
Well done.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你刚是在表扬我吗
Did you just compliment me?
他表扬我了  是吧
He did, didn't he?
听起来是的
Kind of sounded like he did.
我以前很厉害吧
I was good, wasn't I?
还有我跟一个复仇者干了一架还没死
Hey, how about the fact that I fought an Avenger and didn't die?
别沉溺于往事
Let us not dwell on the past.
还得完成计划
We gotta finish our planning.
别在意他
Don't mind him.
你做得很好
You did good.
达伦
Darren.
你是怎么进来的
How the hell did you get in here?
前门没锁  汉克
You left the front door open, Hank.
这回是真的了
It's official.
你老了
You're old.
计划图纸
The plans.
他会杀了他
He will kill him.
你有何贵干
Well, to what do I owe this pleasure?
我有好消息
I have good news.
是吗
Really?
是什么
What's that?
皮姆科技  你一手建立的公司
Pym Tech, the company you created,
马上要成为世界上
is about to become one of the most
效益最好的机构了
profitable operations in the world.
光是明天的买卖就能赚150亿
We're anticipating $15 billion in sales, tomorrow alone.
不用谢了
You're welcome.
我知道很奇怪  但我想你也在场
I know this is odd, but I'd like you to be there.
那是我的时刻  我想让你也看到
This is my moment. I want you to see it.
好的  达伦  可以
Sure, Darren. Yeah, sure.
我会到场的
I'll be there.
你看中我什么了
What did you see in me?
我不懂你什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
多年以前  你选中了我
All those years ago, you picked me.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
我看到了我自己
I saw myself.
那你为什么又把我推开
Then why did you push me away?
因为你太像我了
Because I saw too much of myself.
他知道了  那是陷阱
He knows. He's baiting you.
我们得中止计划
We have to call it off.
我们都在冒险
We're all taking risks.
要是他看到我在这里怎么办
What if he saw me here?
他没看到的  没有可能
He didn't. There's no way.
你怎么能确定
How do you know that?
达伦·克洛斯
达伦  你好
Darren, hi.
霍普  你现在在哪
Hope, where are you right now?
我在家  怎么了
I'm at home. Why?
我刚去见汉克了
I just saw Hank.
他还是和以前一样轻视我
I still get nothing but contempt from him.
别跟他生气  他就是个糟老头
Don't let him rile you up. He's just a senile old man.
所有人都要加班加点的工作
We need to start everyone working around the clock.
马上准备运行生产线
Get the assembly line up and running.
我要加强警备
And I'm tripling security.
所有入口都要设感应器
Full sensors at all entrances
通风口都装上钢制微孔筛
and exterior air vents fitted with steel micro-mesh.
好的  好主意
Great. Good idea.
谢谢你  霍普  有你在我这边真幸运
Thank you, Hope. I'm so lucky to have you on my team.
他要加强警备  他已经疯了还盯上你了
He's tripling security. He's lost his mind, and he's onto you.
但他没有盯上你
But he is not onto you.
他要在所有入口加装人体扫描仪
He's adding full body scanners to all entrances
还要关闭外部通风口
and closing exterior vents.
斯科特怎么进去
How are we gonna get Scott inside?
总水管
The water main.
你没法加强总水管的安保措施
You can't add security to a water main.
水压太强了  但要是我们能减弱水压
The pressure is too strong, but if we can decrease it,
我就能进去
that's how I get in.
得有人在大楼的控制中心
Somebody would have to reach the building's control center
去调节水压
to change the water pressure.
我和汉克得陪在克洛斯身边
Hank and I will be beside Cross.
我们根本不可能做到
How are we supposed to do that?
我们要招兵买马了
So we expand our team.
需要哪些人呢
What do we need?
内部要安插一名假保安
A fake security guard on the inside
负责进入供水系统降压
to de-pressurize the water system,
另一个人要侵入供电系统切断激光光束
somebody else to hack in to the power supply and kill the laser grid,
还要一个人接应我们逃跑
and a getaway guy.
不不不  那三个蠢货不行  绝对不行
No, no. No, no, no. Not those three wombats. No way.
谢谢您的咖啡  女士
Thank you for the coffee, ma'am.
很少会有人被打劫了还邀请劫匪坐坐
It's not too often that you rob a place and then get welcomed back.
因为我们打劫了你
Because we just robbed you.
你知道他是因为偷了台冰沙机被捕的吧
You know that he was arrested for stealing a smoothie machine, right?
是两台冰沙机
Two smoothie machines.
你确定他们能胜任吗
Are you sure they can handle this?
肯定可以  我们可是专业的
Oh, we can handle it. We're professionals.
请原谅我们对你们没什么信心
You'll forgive us if we're not instilled with confidence.
各位都先冷静一下  淡定淡定
Well, hey, everybody just kick back and relax a little bit, man.
我们懂这行
We know our business.
我们可闯入过这老房子  不是吗
We broke into this spooky-ass house, didn't we?
是我放你们进来的
I let you.
那也可以说是我让你放我进来的
Well, one could say that I let you let me.
没事  他们能搞定
Look, it's okay. They can handle this.
对  我们能搞定
Yeah, we can handle it.
-你有他们的证件了吗  -他在系统里了
- You got their credentials? - He's in the system.
我在系统里了
I'm in the system?
你在系统里了
You're in the system.
系统里吗
The system?
好吧  我们死定了
Yeah, we're doomed.
好了  有样东西要给你们看看
All right. There's something you guys need to see.
等你走到这个转角
When you get to this corner,
你的左侧会有三间办公室
there's gonna be three offices on your left side.
我操
Damn!
真是太酷炫了  哥们
Whoa! That's so cool, bro!
听着  过一会儿会很诡异
Now, look, this is gonna get weird, all right?
会很吓人  但其实没事
It's pretty freaky, but it's safe.
不必害怕
There's no reason to be scared.
不不  老子我天不怕地不怕
Oh, no, no. Daddy don't get scared.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
那就好
Good.
绝对是吉普赛人搞的鬼把戏
This is the work of Gypsies.
这是巫术吧
That's witchcraft.
太厉害了
Wow, that's amazing.
感觉就像大卫·科波菲尔那样
That's like some David Copperfield shit.
这是什么魔法吧
That's some kind of wizardry.
是巫术
This is sorcery!
哥们  你是怎么做到的
How'd you do that, bro?
千万别怕  看看你的肩膀
Don't freak out. Look at your shoulder.
滚开  滚开
Get off! Get off!
你不是还说你天不怕地不怕吗
Wait, I thought Daddy didn't get scared!
我让每人吃了半片镇静剂
I gave them each half a Xanax
汉克还给他们解释这套衣服的原理呢
and Hank explained the science of the suit to them.
他们就睡着了
They fell right asleep.
听着  我很感谢你能...
Hey, look, I wanna thank you for...
不  别谢我
No, please don't.
我们这么做都是为了大义
We're all doing this for reasons much bigger than any one of us.
我只是很高兴你还有
I'm just glad that you might have
那么一丝机会可能会成功
a slight chance of maybe pulling this off.
谢谢你为我打气
Hey, thank you, you know, for that pep talk.
老实说  我已经从原来的瞧不起你
You know, the honest truth is, I actually went from despising you
变得快开始喜欢你了
to almost liking you.
你真的应该去写诗
You really should write poetry.
去睡会吧  斯科特
Get some sleep, Scott.
好了  确定一下
All right, just so we're clear,
我们都清楚自己的任务了吧
everyone here knows their role, right?
-戴夫  -负责驾车逃跑
- Dave? - Wheels on the ground.
-科特  -负责搞定监控
- Kurt? - Eyes in the sky.
-路易斯  -你懂的
- Luis? - Oh, man, you know it.
没错  我要穿制服
You know what? I get to wear a uniform.
-就是这样  -路易斯
- That's what's up. - Luis.
抱歉  我清楚任务  我只是太兴奋了
I'm sorry. I'm good. I'm good. I'm just excited.
而且你的女朋友真的很性感
Plus, your girlfriend's really hot.
看到她我也会特别紧张
So, you know, that makes me nervous, too.
你真的很漂亮  女士
And you are very beautiful, ma'am.
-我的天哪  -她不是我的...
- Oh, my Lord. - She's not my...
对了  我想到个策略
You know what? I was thinking of a tactic,
我卧底进去时可以用
like when I go undercover.
比如吹口哨  你懂我的意思吧  融入进去
Like a whistling. You know what I'm saying? To like, blend in.
不行  别吹口哨  不准吹
No. Don't whistle. No whistling.
这又不是表演才艺节目  不准吹
It's not The Andy Griffith Show. No whistling.
一区一切正常
All clear in Sector One.
进来
Step out.
没问题
All clear.
准备就绪
We're set.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
设备上线
Utilities online.
你在干什么
Hey! What are you doing?
头儿让我来检查下这  我就来了
Uh... Boss-man said to secure the area, so I'm securing it.
我就是头儿
I'm the boss.
控制室1.3
Utilities 1.3...
水位正在下降
Water level is dropping!
爬到抽气管上
Coming up on extraction pipe.
我看到了
All right, I see it.
拜托了  我得爬上去
All right, come on, I gotta get up there.
没错  没错  就是这样
That's it. That's it, guys! Yes!
没错  我们做到了  做到了  快点
Yes! You got it! You got it! Come on!
好了  起飞吧  安东蚁
All right, let's fly, Ant-thony.
蚁人进入大楼了
The Ant-Man is in the building.
皮姆刚到  时间正好
Pym's pulling up. Right on time.
外面还有辆福特皇冠
Got a Crown Vic right outside there.
有什么问题吗
This is problem?
福特皇冠是卧底警察
Considering the Crown Vic's the most commonly used car
最常开的车
for undercover cops, man,
没错  出问题了
yes, this is problem.
是皮姆
That's Pym.
不
Oh, no.
我在部署子弹蚂蚁
I'm deploying the bullet ants.
拟猛蚁亚科什么什么蚁
Paraponera clavata de Merna Merna...
不记得学名叫什么  但这人惨了
I don't remember what it's called, but I feel bad for this guy.
瞧瞧  这还差不多
See? That's what I'm talking about.
这就是我所说的在严肃的
That's what I call an unfortunate casualty
行动中不幸的受害者
in a very serious operation.
信号诱饵就位
Signal decoy in place.
凶巴巴美女也搞定了  斯科特
Mean, pretty lady did good, Scott.
看来皮姆被逮捕了
Looks like Pym's getting arrested.
斯科特  出问题了
Scott, we have problem.
问题  什么问题
Problem? What's the problem?
戴夫  戴夫  我们可没这计划
Dave! Dave, that's not part of plan!
听我说
Listen to me.
如果我不进这大楼  有人就会死
If I don't get into this building, people will die.
有那么夸张吗
That's awfully dramatic.
是不是在逗我
Are you kidding me?
问题解决了
Problem solved.
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
终于来了
There he is.
刚刚好  走吧
Just in time. Come on.
十二项验证
12-point verification.
有点过头了  你不觉得吗  达伦
Little over-the-top, don't you think, Darren?
正在确认授权
Confirming authorization level.
防范于未然嘛
Well, you can never be too safe.
准许进入
Access granted.
得为你鼓鼓掌  达伦
Gotta hand it to you, Darren.
你真的做到了
You really did it.
这还只是一部分  汉克
And you only know the half of it, Hank.
前往第二目标位置
Arriving in second position.
全速前进  安东蚁  冲吧
All right, top speed, Ant-thony. Let's go!
继续向指定位置前进
Proceeding to command position.
我马上就回来  安东蚁
I'll be right back, Ant-thony.
好了  各位  我到了
All right, guys. I'm in position.
我要给蚂蚁们发指令了
I'm gonna signal the ants.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
各就各位
Assume formation.
好了  你们这些可爱的小家伙
All right, you cute little crazies,
烧坏这些服务器吧
let's fry these servers!
上吧兄弟们
Let's go get 'em, buddy!
服务器已被毁坏
Servers are fried.
备份数据均已被擦除
Data backup completely erased.
正在前往粒子实验室
Heading to the particle chamber.
你好  克洛斯博士
Hello, Dr. Cross.
我的伙伴们答应了你的条件
My associates have agreed to your terms.
太好了
Wonderful.
卡森先生向这几位先生引荐了我
Mr. Carson introduced me to these fine gentlemen here.
他们是九头蛇的代表们
They're representatives of Hydra.
他们不是曾经那样了
They're not what they were.
他们正在进行有趣的工作
They're doing some interesting work.
而我也很享受这样
And I'm enjoying myself.
你一直把技术藏起来不给我
You tried to hide your technology from me.
现在你自食恶果了吧
And now it's gonna blow up in your face.
我早就预料到你会出拳揍我
I mean, I saw that punch coming a mile away,
可我还以为这一拳会很软弱无力呢
but I just figured it'd be all pathetic and weak.
那你想错了
Well, you figured wrong.
我见过这辆车
I know this van.
有人吗
Anybody home?
好了各位  我到了
All right, guys. I'm here.
正在安装炸弹
I'm setting the charges.
各位干得很好  接下来交给我吧
Great job, guys. I'll take it from here.
安东蚁  辛苦了
Good boy, Ant-thony.
最后目标位
Final position.
各位  激光光栅关了吗
Guys, how we looking on that laser grid?
-快了  -并没搞定
- Almost. - No, you're not.
-马上就好了  -并没有
- I'm getting close! - No, you're not.
旧金山警察局
San Francisco P.D.!
从车里出来
Out of the van!
我知道你们在里面
I know you're in there!
再快点
Make it go faster.
哥们  别再催我了
Dude, seriously.
准备跃入  听到没  科特
Ready to jump. Do you read, Kurt?
马上就好
So close.
-等等  再等一会  -别动
- Okay, hold up! Wait a minute! - Freeze!
有个和我长得一模一样的黑人
There was a black guy that looked exactly like me
袭击了我们  把我们关进这破车里
who attacked us and put us in the back of this disgusting van.
-给我出来  -我这不是在出来嘛
- Get out of the van! - Okay, I'm coming.
别紧张
Take it easy!
我不走  快上
No, I will not move! Go now!
等等
Wait!
什么  为什么又要等等
What? What do you mean, "Wait"?
搞什么
What? What?
小家伙
Hey, little guy.
我一直都怀疑你还偷藏了一套衣服
I always suspected you had a suit stored away somewhere.
那么问题来了
Which begs the question,
这位新蚁人是谁
who is the new Ant-Man?
这位让我敬爱的导师更加信任的人是谁
Who is the man that my beloved mentor trusted even more than me?
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
殉道者
A martyr
反抗了社会也付出了代价
who took on the system and paid the price,
失去了他的家庭和他唯一的女儿
losing his family and his only daughter in the process.
正好是你的口味  汉克
Exactly your kind of guy, Hank!
他越了狱  没有留下任何线索
He escapes his jail cell without leaving any clue as to how.
然后神奇地消失了
And then he disappears magically,
虽然身上一分钱都没有
despite having no money to his name.
现在他把蚁人服带来了
And now he brings me the Ant-Man suit.
唯一能与我的发明相提并论的设计
The only thing that can rival my creation.
达伦  别这么做
Darren, don't do this.
如果你把它卖给这些人
If you sell to these men,
一定会引发世界混乱
it's gonna be chaos.
我已经卖了
I already have.
而且多亏了你
And for twice the price,
卖了两倍的价格
thanks to you.
要成功侵入复联大楼可不容易
It's not easy to successfully infiltrate an Avengers facility.
庆幸的是  消息传千里
Thankfully, word travels fast.
我会把黄衫卖给他们
I'll sell them the Yellowjacket,
不过粒子我就自己留着了
but I'm keeping the particle to myself.
这可不烧柴油
They don't run on diesel.
如果想要燃料  就得来找我
If you want the fuel, you'll have to come to me.
你会怎么称呼全世界
What do you call the only man
唯一一位手握最强大武器的人
who can arm the most powerful weapon in the world?
世界上最强大的人
The most powerful man in the world.
你为我感到自豪了吗
You proud of me yet?
现在收手还来得及  达伦
You can stop this, Darren. It's not too late.
早已经来不及了
It's been too late for a long time now.
达伦
Darren!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
他照顾不好你  就像你也照顾不好我
He wasn't any more capable of caring for you than he was for me.
这不是原来的你
This is not who you are.
你的大脑化学物质被粒子改变了
It's the particles altering your brain chemistry.
等等  等等
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
你说得对  必须我亲自动手
You're right. I have to be the one to do it.
好戏来了
Here we go.
把  枪  放  下
Drop your gun.
那天晚上我去他家本来是想杀他
You know, I came to the house the other night to kill him,
可你当时也在
but you were there.
你走火入魔了  我能帮你  把枪放下
You're sick and I can help you. Just put the gun down.
我当时还没想杀你
I wasn't ready to kill you then,
但我现在准备好了
but I think I am now!
把枪放下
Drop your gun now!
你站错队了  霍普
You picked the wrong side, Hope.
爸爸
Dad!
汉克  不
Hank, no.
不  汉克
No, Hank.
汉克  听着  你会没事的
Hank? Listen, you're gonna be okay.
你会没事的
All right? You're gonna be just fine.
把衣服脱了  不然我一枪崩了你再扒衣服
Take the suit off, or I'll blow your brains out and peel it off.
皮姆科技
皮姆科技公司发生紧急情况
We got a 10-33 at Pym Tech.
请求紧急支援
Request immediate backup!
走走走
Go, go, go!
带我去屋顶
Get me to the roof.
提前无线电联系
And radio ahead.
我去把直升机准备好
I want to make sure the helicopter is ready to take off.
你们俩
You two,
从保险库出来的东西一律格杀勿论
kill anything that comes out of that vault!
爸  你能动吗
Dad, can you move?
我们得带他离开这里
We need to get him out of here.
去拿衣服
Go get that suit.
斯科蒂
Hey, Scotty.
我是不是救了你的小命
Hey, did I save your life?
斯科蒂
Scotty?
谢谢你  路易斯
Thank you, Luis.
-我们是好人吗  -是
- Are we the good guys? - Yeah.
我们是好人  对吧
We're the good guys, right?
没错  我们是好人
Yeah, we're the good guys.
感觉有点奇怪
Feels kinda weird, you know.
嗯  但任务还没结束
Yeah, but we're not done yet.
在爆炸之前快离开这里
Get out of here before this place blows!
该死  忘了那个家伙
Damn it! That guy.
喂  我们要出去了
Hey! We're getting out of here!
炸弹在倒数了
The charges are set.
我们得赶紧想办法离开这  快点
We've gotta find a way out of here. And fast.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不会死的
I'm not gonna die.
你也不会的
And neither are you.
这可不是钥匙链
It's not a keychain.
这里乱成一团了  枪声四起
It's total chaos in here! Multiple shots fired!
还有一辆坦克
And there's a tank.
谁能帮我一下
A little help!
我来
I got it.
我们需要找一个医生
We need a doctor!
交给我们吧
We've got him.
谢谢
Thank you.
走吧
Let's go!
安东蚁
Ant-thony!
走吧
Go!
你会后悔的
You're gonna regret that.
等等  快出来
Wait a minute! Get out of that van!
-什么  -快从车里出来
- What? - Get out of that van!
太吵了  有辆坦克  我听不清你说话
It's too loud, there's a tank. I can't hear you!
你疯了吗  把枪放下
Are you crazy? Put the gun down!
窗户
The windows!
你觉得靠抢劫能阻止未来吗
Did you think you could stop the future with a heist?
根本就不止是抢劫
It was never just a heist!
把枪放下
Put the gun down!
发现他了  在那里  快快快
Okay, I got him, I got him. There he is! Go, go, go!
我们得迫降在某个地方
We gotta set her down somewhere.
我要摧毁你
I'm gonna disintegrate you!
播放治疗乐队的《摧毁》
Playing Disintegration by the Cure.
快报警
Call 911!
没关系的
It's okay.
不许动  把手举起来  举起来
Freeze! Put your hands up! Get them up!
斯科特
Scott?
帕克斯顿  你得听我说
Paxton, you have to listen to me!
帕克斯顿  掉头  让我回去
Paxton, turn around! Take me back!
我是要让你回去  回监狱
I am taking you back. To prison.
那后院里有东西需要被赶紧摧毁掉
There's something in that backyard that needs to be destroyed.
在捕蚊灯里  有
In the bug zapper. There...
给我打住  你的幻想太离谱了
You need to desist right now! Your delusions are out of hand.
所有单位注意  温特街840号发生一起入室抢劫
All units, we have a 2-36 in progress at 840 Winter Street.
-凯西  -那是我家
- Cassie! - That's my house.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
帕克斯顿  让我帮忙
Paxton, let me help!
别动
Don't move.
让我帮忙吧
Let me help!
玛姬  发生什么事了
Maggie! What's going on?
他抓住了凯西
He's got Cassie!
-亲爱的  谁抓了凯西  -那个东西
- Who's got Cassie, honey? - That thing.
-东西  -我不知道  不知道
- Thing? - I don't know! I don't know!
你是怪物吗
Are you a monster?
我看着像怪物吗
Do I look like a monster?
我想要我爸爸
I want my daddy!
我也想要你爸爸
I want your daddy, too.
你来了
There you are.
爸爸  是你吗
Daddy, is that you?
嗨  小花生
Hi, peanut.
你为什么不找个和你差不多大的玩
Why don't you pick on someone your own size?
小个子  你去了哪里啊
Now, where did you go, little guy?
在这里
There you are.
不只有我
Not just me!
该死
Damn it!
快去吧
Go! Go!
斯科特需要我们  你懂我的意思吗
Scotty needs us, you know what I'm saying?
没什么能够阻止我们
Ain't nothing gonna stop us.
-后退  慢慢地后退  -好吧
- Back it up. Back it up, slow. - Yeah.
后退
Back it up.
再后退
-我们就退后吧  行吗  -够了吗
- We just back it up, okay? - That's it.
-后退  -没错
- Back it up. - That's right.
继续退后吗
Backin' up?
对  退后
Yep, just backin' up.
不不  快继续
No, no. Just back it up.
你侮辱了我  斯科特
You insult me, Scott.
你的存在对我来说就是侮辱
Your very existence is insulting to me.
你要是大一点  打你就容易多了
You know, it'd be much easier to hit you if you were bigger.
我同意
Yeah, I agree.
凯西
Cassie!
我会让你看看你是多么微不足道
I'm gonna show you just how insignificant you are.
凯西  我来了
Cassie! I'm coming!
这狗长得也忒丑了
That's a messed-up looking dog.
我将摧毁你所爱的一切
I'm gonna destroy everything you love.
不许动  旧金山警局
Freeze! S.F.P.D.
我进不去
I can't break through.
是钛合金的  你这个蠢货
It's titanium, you idiot!
-带她离开这  -快走
- Get her out of here. - Come on.
抱歉  亲爱的
Sorry, sweetheart.
你得帮你爸爸赎罪
You have to help Daddy pay for his mistakes.
站在我身后  知道吗
You stay behind me, okay?
站在我身后
Stay behind me.
我得缩小到比分子还小才能进去
I'm gonna have to shrink between the molecules to get in there.
离我们远点
Get away from us!
爸爸  救命
Daddy, help!
凯西  我爱你
I love you, Cassie.
爸爸  你在哪里
Daddy, where are you?
你会变成亚原子级
You would go subatomic.
不
Oh, no.
你会进入一个现实
You would enter a reality
在那里一切关于时间和空间的概念
where all concepts of time and space...
没有意义了
become irrelevant...
都没有意义了
一切关于时间和空间的概念都没有意义了
all concepts of time and space become irrelevant...
爸爸  回来
Come back, Daddy!
因为你会不断缩小
as you shrink for all eternity...
你所知
Everything that you know
和所爱的一切
and love,
都将一去不复返
gone forever.
爸爸  你在哪里
Daddy, where are you?
你在哪里
Where are you?
你在哪里啊
-爸爸  -凯西
- Daddy! - Cassie.
爸爸  回来
Come back, Daddy!
不要乱动调节器
Do not screw with the regulator!
爸爸
Daddy!
我好爱你
I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
很爱很爱
So much.
房顶上有个大洞
You know, there's a big hole in the roof.
抱歉
Sorry.
-她没事吧  -嗯  她没事
- Is she all right? - Yeah, she's fine.
妈妈
Mommy!
她没事  她没事
She's fine, she's fine.
拜托  斯科特
Scott, please.
你什么都不记得了吗
You don't remember anything?
汉克  我记不得了
Hank. I don't.
肯定还有些什么的
There must be something else.
好吧  我觉得人类的大脑
Well, I suppose the human mind
是没法理解这种经历的
just can't comprehend the experience,
但你却成功了
but you made it.
你进去以后
You went in,
又出来了
and you got out.
真棒
It's amazing.
斯科特
Scott,
我带你出去
I'll walk you out.
好好休息
Get some rest.
这真的有可能吗
Is it possible?
什么时候的事
When did this happen?
没什么事
Nothing's happening.
等等  算是有点什么事吧
Whoa. Hold on. Something's kind of happening.
要真是这样
Well, if that's the case,
再给我来一枪
shoot me again.
我不知道你刚在干嘛
Yeah. I don't know what you were doing,
对我又抱又亲的
grabbing and kissing me like that.
我也有点小惊讶呢
I'm a little surprised myself.
我得去个地方  一会见  汉克
I have to get somewhere. I'll see you later, Hank.
霍普  你真是的
Really, Hope.
斯科特
Scott.
-满嘴胡话  -没错
- You're full of shit. - Oh, yeah.
斯科特  我今天见了我们警监
Scott, I met with my captain today.
他想要你出狱那晚的报告
He wanted a report on the night that you got out of jail.
摄像头出现了故障
Something happened with the cameras.
一些电路被烧坏了
Some circuits got fried.
但我跟他说你是走正规程序出去的
But I told him that you were processed correctly.
真的吗
Really?
是的
Well, yeah.
不能因为电子故障就把凯西的爸爸送回监狱  对吧
Can't be sending Cassie's dad back to jail on a technical glitch, right?
谢谢你  帕克斯顿
Thank you, Paxton.
我太感动了
I'm blown away.
谢谢你为凯西所做的一切
Thank you for everything you do for Cassie.
不甚荣幸
Well, that's my pleasure.
不过这次  我是为了你
But, no. This one, I did for you.
好尴尬
This is awkward.
-没错  -没错
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
这事之后我们还有什么可谈的呢
I mean, what do we even talk about after all of that?
-我知道  -什么
- Oh, I know. - What?
我今天第一次横翻筋斗
I did my first cartwheel today.
什么
What?
没错  她练了一个星期了
Yeah. She has been practicing all week.
今天真是见证奇迹的时刻
But today was the magic day.
我用手机录下来了  看
I recorded it on my phone. Here.
不  这不可能是凯西  这不是你
No, that can't be Cassie. That's not you.
是她
Yeah, it is.
这分明是专业体操运动员  不可能是你
This is a professional gymnast. There is no way that's you.
的确就是她
Yeah, that's her.
好狗狗
Good boy.
亲爱的  真的太棒了
Sweetie, that's pretty amazing, peanut.
抱歉
Sorry.
工作上的事
It's work.
好的
All right.
这样吧  把事实告诉我
Here's the deal. Just give me the facts.
讲重点  只讲重点
Just the facts. Only the facts.
呼气  专注  简简单单
Breathe. Focus. Keep it simple.
行  行  没问题的
No, no, no. No doubt, no doubt. Okay.
我和我表哥伊格纳西奥去艺术馆
So, I'm at this art museum with my cousin Ignacio, right?
是一个抽象表现主义的展览
And there was this, like, abstract expressionism exhibit.
但你知道的  我比较喜欢新立体主义的作品
But you know me, I'm more like a Neo-Cubist kind of guy, right?
但有个人叫罗斯科的人非常棒  天呐
But there was this one Rothko that was sublime, bro! Oh, my God!
路易斯
Luis.
好了  抱歉  抱歉
Okay, sorry. Sorry.
我就是太兴奋了
You know, I just get excited and stuff.
但不管怎么说  伊格纳西奥告诉我
But anyway, Ignacio tells me,
"我昨晚在焦点酒吧
"Yo, I met this crazy-fine writer chick
遇到一个超正点的作家妹子  超级正点
at the Spot last night. Like fine-fine.
特别特别正点  然后他
Like crazy-stupid fine." And he
过去跟酒保说
goes up to the bartender and goes,
看那个和我一起的妹子  懂我意思不
"Look at the girl I'm with. You know what I'm sayin'?
她超正的  对吧
"She's crazy-stupid fine, right?"
酒保说  是啊  的确超正
The bartender's all like, "Yeah, crazy-stupid fine."
所以这个作家妹子告诉伊格纳西奥
So this writer chick tells Ignacio,
我可是小道八卦界女王
"Yo, I'm like a boss in the world of guerrilla journalism,
我和幕后大佬关系可好了
"And I got mad connects with the peeps behind the curtains,
你懂我说得不
"You know what I'm saying?"
伊格纳西奥就问  真的呀
Ignacio's like, "For real?"
她说  真的啊
And she's like, "Yeah, you know what,
我不能告诉你我线人是谁
I can't tell you who my contact is,
因为他和复联一起工作
"Because he works with the Avengers."
天呐
Oh, no.
这人听上去很厉害呢
Yeah, and this dude sounds like a badass, man.
他走过去跟她说
Like, he comes up to her and says,
"我在找个超级英雄界的新人
"Yo, I'm looking for this dude who's new on the scene,
"刚初来乍到
"who's flashing his fresh tack,
"技能出众的人  你知道谁吗"
"who's got, like, bomb moves, right? Who you got?"
她说  什么人都有啊
And she's like, "Well, we got everything nowaday.
有会蹦的
We got a guy who jumps.
会飞的  还有爬墙的
"We got a guy who swings, we got a guy who crawls up the walls.
你得说具体点
"You gotta be more specific."
他说  我要找个能缩小的
And he's like, "I'm looking for a guy that shrinks."
我说  靠  我很紧张
And I'm, like, "Damn!". I got all nervous
因为我要为你保守秘密
'cause I'd keep mad secrets for you, bro.
所以我问伊格纳西奥
So I asked Ignacio,
"那个狠角色是不是让超正作家找你
"Did the badass tell the stupid-fine writer chick
让你来找我  因为我和他要找的
to tell you to tell me, because I'm tight with Ant-Man,
那个蚁人关系很好吗
"That he's looking for him?"
然后呢  他说什么
And? What'd he say?
他说  没错
He said, "Yes."
蚁  人
我想给你看个东西
There's something I want to show you.
力量是无法摧毁的
I realized you can't destroy power.
只能尽量不被歹人触及
All you can do is make sure that it's in the right hands.
这个升级版原型衣
This is an advanced prototype
是我和你母亲一同研发的
that your mother and I worked on together.
她都没有机会用
She never got to use it.
但我现在明白了  这是我们为你造的
But now I realize that we were... We were working on it for you.
是时候完成这件衣服了
Maybe it's time we finished it.
是时候了
It's about damn time.
片尾还有彩蛋
嗨  队长
Hey, Cap!
一周前做这件事肯定更容易
This would have been a lot easier a week ago.
-如果我给托尼打电话  -他不会相信我们的
- If we call Tony... - He won't believe us.
就算他相信
Even if he did...
协议应该不准他帮忙吧
Who knows if the Accords will let him help.
我们现在只能靠自己了
We're on our own.
或许不用
Maybe not.
我认识一个人
I know a guy.
蚁人将于美队3回归